# **SIRUI ZHU**

Portfolio available at : siruizhu.github.io

## SELECTED PROJECTS

### China's Long March to space

https://graphics.reuters.com/SPACE-EXPLORATION-MOON/0100B0BH0NZ/i ndex.html Researching China space program and processing data. Using After effects for animations, Illustrator for rockets illustrations, using Ai2html and responsive web design.

### A look at Alibaba's "Double 11" shopping day, the world's largest online retail event

https://graphics.reuters.com/SINGLES-DAY-ALIBABA/0100B30E24T/index.ht ml Researching on Chinese Singles' Day shopping event. Gathering and processing data. Using illustrations and animation to highlight the visuals, using JavaScript to develop interactive chart.

### Vaping crisis

https://graphics.reuters.com/HEALTH-VAPING/0100B4RB2H6/index.html Researching on vaping issue in the U.S., came up with ideas and illustrations, using JavaScript to develop interactive charts.

### Apple products made in China could face tariffs by year's end

https://graphics.reuters.com/USA-TRADE-APPLE/0100B25R11Y/index.html Collaborate with a colleague. Data processing and research. Icon illustrations and interactive scrollytelling.

### Treasure of architecture: China to better protect architecture relics

https://siruizhu.github.io/cultural--relics/ API to access the data. Interactive graphics showing all cultural relics names, classifications and distribution.

### Recently

I'm working on a visual story based on my own experience as I'm stucking at my home in Wuhan. The idea is to record my daily life and show my notes/diaries during the lockdown.

### **EDUCATION**

# Lede Program for Data Journalism, Columbia University

May 2

018 - Dec. 2018 New York, USA

Courses: Python, data analysis with pandas, matplotlib, SQL, JavaScript, D3.js, basic machine learning (regression and prediction) and text analysis, web app development, geographic analysis with QGIS, Scrollytelling.

# M.A., Broadcast Journalism, University of Sheffield

Sept. 2014 - Sept. 2015 Sheffield, UK

Portfolio: London's Chinatown Feels the Squeeze of Rent Rises (video)

# B.A., Broadcasting and Compering, Wuhan University

Sept. 2010 - June 2014 Wuhan, China

Dissertation: Analysis of China Reality Show from the Perspective of Communication.

Rm 1201, Building 2, District 10, Dangdai Guoji Huayuan Guanggu Ave., Wuhan, Hubei. 430205

**Tel:** (+86) 18607165112 | **Email:** surizhu9@gmail.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Data: Python, pandas, matplotlib, SQL, APIs,

Selenium, BeautifulSoup

Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, D3.js, Ai2html

Mapping: QGIS, Mapbox, Leaflet Services: Github, Git, Travis, Heroku **Applications:** Adobe Illustrator,

Photoshop, After Effects, Adobe Premiere, Final

Cut Pro, Edius

**Language:** Mandarin(Native)

English(Professional)

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Thomson Reuters | New York, USA

Data visualization developer intern

April 1st 2019 to Dec. 31 2019

Designing and developing interactive & static graphics for daily news and special reports; Reporting data-driven stories, topics include immigration, finance, culture and environment.

# Wuhan Dyclub Data Technology Lit.Co. Wuhan, China

*Training Supervisor* Nov. 2016 - May 2018 Organized more than twenty Dyclub data journalism online trainings. Managed and wrote articles on Wechat channel's special column "Weekly Data Journalism." Operated visualization tool Dydata.io, executed data analysis on users. Organized the "Third Data Journalism Competition" and award ceremony.

### **Hubei Televisions** | Wuhan, China

TV Producer Mar 2016 - Oct. 2016 Produced children's reality show and wrote children's show scripts.

### UK Chinese Times | London, UK

News Editor intern June 2015 - July 2015 Edited international news pieces

### China National Radio | Beijing

News Editor intern Feb. 2013 - May 2013 Edited radio news, worked on 2013 NPC and CPPCC reporting for two weeks.

### **AWARDS & VOLUNTEER**

Excellent Journalist of Wuhan University 2011.6 **Excellent Student for University Article Writing** Competition for Xinhai Revolution 100th Sheffield Student Union Charity Hitchhike 2015.3 Wuhan Green NGO Oct. 2011